Shall we be going, then?
Lady Amira!
Favaro!
I'm waiting for sunrises again
（マルチネ）
では そろそろ行きましょうか
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
アーミラ嬢！
ぐわっ！
Rage of Bahamut
ファバロオオオ！
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
（ラファエル）
ミカエル！
Michael!
Maintain composure!
（ウリエル）
うろたえるな！
But this means...
だが これは…
（ミカエル）
分かっている
I'm aware!
ついに現れたのだ
“神魔(しんま)の鍵”が！
The Transcendent Key is finally complete!
（バッカス）
ベルゼビュートといやあ
Beelzebub?
Ain't he a high-ranking demon that protects the land of Helheim?
ヘルヘイムの地を護(まも)る
上級の悪魔じゃねえか
（アザゼル）
鍵の女のバックには ヤツがいた
He was the one pulling the strings for the key girl.
（リタ）
けど そいつの単独犯
ってわけでもないんでしょ？
But there's no way he pulled it off all by himself.
（アザゼル）
側近のマルチネも 一緒だ
His aide, Martinet, is working with him.
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
マルチネ…
さぞ お美しい女性なんでしょうね
Martinet? She must be really pretty with a name like that!
（アザゼル）
男だ
It's a he.
ぐわく…
それ 本当の名前かしら
Could that be his real name?
（バッカス）
例の賞金首か？
Of the guy I was talking about?
A demon having the ability to turn a human into a demon isn't all that far-fetched.
確かに 悪魔なら
人を悪魔に変える魔術を使えても
おかしくねえな
（リタ）
悪魔だとは限らないわ
There's no guarantee he's a demon.
（リタ）
その魔術が
Especially if the little zombie daughter of a former doctor could see through his magic.
元医者の娘のゾンビに
見破られるくらいならね
急ぎましょう
Let's hurry.
Before she becomes one with Bahamut, right?
早くしないと あのお子様
バハムートに
なっちゃうんじゃない？
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
There's no need to worry!
（ミカエル）
動ずる必要はない
我らが結界を維持しているかぎり
As long as we maintain this barrier,
the key cannot make contact with Bahamut!
鍵が
バハムートと接触することはない
Jeanne?
ジャンヌ？
いけない！
No!
Raphael!
（ウリエル･ミカエル）
ラファエル！
Why would Jeanne do this to Raphael?!
なぜ ジャンヌがラファエルを！
No.
いや…
Something is different about Jeanne.
あれはジャンヌであって
ジャンヌではない
今の彼女の魂は
邪悪な力で満ちあふれている
There's an aura of evil permeating her soul.
（ウリエル）
どうして そのようなことが…
How can that be?!
ウリエル そっちへ行くぞ！
Uriel! She's coming your way!
ダメだ このままでは…
It's no use! I can't keep this up!
Uriel!
ウリエル！
マズい
This is bad!
何とか助かった…
I managed to survive.
Favaro!
ファバロオオオ！
が… エイボスが
However, Abos is...
ぐわっ！
（ベルゼビュート）
貴様の欲するものは
What you desire is right here, Bahamut!
ここにあるぞ バハムート！
Favaro!
ファバロ！
You can't honestly have stooped to being a demon!
貴様 本当に
悪魔になり果ててしまったのか？
Are you really going to let these
lousy demons conquer your spirit?!
お前の心は あんな悪魔ごときに
屈してしまうのか？
アーミラ嬢の運命を
変えるのだろう？
What happened to changing Lady Amira's fate?!
Say something!
何とか言え！
Favaro!
ファバロ～！
Kaisar!
（リタ）
カイザル！
You all right, Hammer Head?
（バッカス）
無事か？　ハンマーヘッド
Bacchus!
（カイザル）
バッカス…
（バッカス）
すまねえ 若干 定員オーバーだわ
Sorry. We're a tad over capacity.
（カイザル）
大天使ミカエル
Michael the Archangel!
And is that...
それに あれは…
ジャンヌか？
Jeanne?!
なぜ あのようなお姿に？
Why does she look like that?
（リタ）
あの聖女様
魔術で悪魔になっちゃったのよ
The great saint was transformed into a demon with sorcery.
（カイザル）
なっ… 悪魔だと？
A demon?! Could it be the same magic used on Favaro?
ファバロと同じ術なのか？
ヤベえ
Crap. She's noticed us.
目が… 合っちまった
（ベルゼビュート）
審判の時だ
The time of judgment has come.
Hansa!
（バッカス）
ハンサ～！
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
くわあああ！
Bacchus! Jeanne!
バッカス！　ジャンヌ！
You're still not dead, son of Lidfard?
（アザゼル）
まだ死んでなかったか
リドファルドの息子よ
Azazel! What are you doing here?!
（カイザル）
貴様 アザゼル！
なぜ ここに？
I wish I could stay here and slaughter you, but I'm afraid I have a prior engagement.
本来なら
この場で屠(ほふ)ってやりたいところだが
あいにく 先約があるのでな
I'm a little too busy to deal with you guys.
お前たちの相手をするほど
暇ではないのだ
I see. If that's how you really want it, then have at it.
そうか
お前が それでもいいなら
かまわないんだがな
What do you mean?
何の話だ？
If you run off now, you'll have lost to us forever.
このままじゃ
私たちの勝ち逃げになるだろ？
Don't pretend that you
measly humans have me beat.
人間ごときが
俺に勝ったつもりになるなよ
The next time we meet...
次に会ったときは…
（カイザル）次があればいいがな
（アザゼル）ん？
If there is a next time.
We'll never cross paths again if the world meets with destruction.
（カイザル）
世界が滅んでしまえば
もう二度と会うこともないだろう
フン… 勝手に言ってろ
Say what you will.
May you be destroyed with the world!
世界と共に滅びるがいい
Take this with you.
（リタ）
持っていきなさい
If you can get some of it into ol' Afro...
あのアフロに これをぶち込めば…
（リタ）きゃあ！
（ハンサ）くわっ！
Not again!
（カイザル）
またかあああ！
You stupid duck!
（リタ）
このバカアヒル！
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
That's three falls in one day now!
落下するのは 本日３回目か
I've changed my mind.
気が変わった
I am going to settle things with you guys. Personally.
貴様たちは
俺の手で けりをつけてやる
必ずな
Very well! That's fine by me!
いいだろう 望むところだ
Man, am I gonna be sore tomorrow!
こりゃあ 明日は筋肉痛だぜ！
If I'm still alive, that is.
生きてればな
This is the last of my antidotes.
（リタ）
今ある解毒剤は これが最後…
Now or never!
ここだ！
（ジャンヌ）うっ！
（ハンサ）くわあ！
I've decided.
決めたわ
For my last supper, I want that duck roasted with olive oil.
最後の晩餐(ばんさん)はアヒル
あんたのオリーブ焼きよ
Personally, I want some tasty booze!
（バッカス）
俺は うめえ酒がいいなあ！
（ハンサ）
くわっ！
（リタ･バッカス）ああっ！
（ハンサ）くわっ！
（ジャンヌ）
ミカ…
That's...
あれは！
Forgive me, O maiden.
許せ 乙女よ
ミカエル様…
Lord Michael!
It's all right, Jeanne.
いいのです ジャンヌ
This is our punishment...
これは罰なのです
ゼウスを失い
For losing Zeus and forgetting how to work with humans the way we did 2,000 years ago.
二千年前のように人と手を取り合う
すべを忘れてしまった我らへの
You bear no blame whatsoever.
あなたには何の非もありません
But, I...
（ジャンヌ）
しかし 私は…
I...
私は！
Jeanne.
（ミカエル）
ジャンヌ
あなたは神に祝福されし乙女
You are a maiden blessed by the gods—
one who shall guide the people.
そして 人々を導く者
覚えておきなさい
Always know this.
この器がなくなろうとも
私の魂は あなたと共に…
Though my physical vessel may
cease to be, my spirit is always with you.
Lord Michael!
ミカエル様！
Looks like Jeanne's back to normal.
（バッカス）
ジャンヌは何とかなったようだな
Bacchus, over there!
（ハンサ）
バッカス！　見てください！
That must be it.
あそこね
So, where should we park the carriage?
（バッカス）
さて 馬車を どこに寄せるか…
We're not going to park it.
（リタ）
寄せる必要なんてないわ
（バッカス）はい？
（ハンサ）くわ？
Huh?
We're going to ram the carriage right into it.
このまま馬車ごと突っ込むのよ
Still persisting, I see.
まだ耐え忍んでいたか
You angels are an impertinent bunch.
こざかしい天使どもだ
Time for you to make your exit now.
だが そろそろ ご退場 願おう
Beelzebub!
（アザゼル）
ベルゼビュートオオオ！
It's payback time, Beelzebub!
借りを返しに来たぞ
ベルゼビュート！
Cooperating with the gods and humans now, are you?
（ベルゼビュート）
神や人間と手を組んだか
You're a fool to your very core, Azazel.
つくづく愚かだな アザゼル
（ハンサ）
くわっ くわっ くわっ…
くわあ～！
あんた… ホント めんどくさいわ
You're a real pain in the neck, you know.
You dumbass!
バカヤロー！
くわっ！
く～わ～！
これはこれは
とんだ神様のお出ましですね
Well, well. An illustrious god has come to visit.
You and your damn concoctions...
（バッカス）
てめえ その薬…
We've crossed swords so many times before that it's clear to me.
（カイザル）
これまで幾度となく
剣を交えてきたからこそ 分かる
ファバロ お前は本当に…
You truly have become a demon, Favaro.
悪魔になってしまったのだな
Farewell, my friend!
さらばだ 友よ
アーミラ嬢
Lady Amira...
Kaisar.
（ラヴァレイ）
カイザル君
Captain Lavalley! What are you doing here?
（カイザル）
ラヴァレイ隊長
どうして ここに…
The Orléans Knights followed Jeanne to this land.
（ラヴァレイ）
我らオルレアン騎士団も
ジャンヌを追って
この地にやって来たのだ
We'll soon have this flying fortress neutralized.
この飛行要塞も
まもなく制圧が完了する
Neutralized?
（カイザル）
制圧？
Yes. You've done a splendid job.
（ラヴァレイ）
ああ よく頑張ってくれた
Look there.
あれを見なさい
（カイザル）
神々の降臨…
The gods are descending?!
Everything's fine now.
（ラヴァレイ）
もう大丈夫だ
Now let's get out of here, quickly.
さあ ここから早く脱出するぞ
（リタ）
その男から離れなさい！
Get away from that man!
Rita?
リタ？
（リタ）
きゃあ！
Lady Amira!
（カイザル）
アーミラ嬢！
The desire for something can make a person strong.
何かを望む心は人を強くする
Nothing is more pleasing than the sound of that mighty resolve being broken!
その強い心が折れる音は
何よりも心地よい
（アーミラ）
ファバ…
Fava...
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
Illustration: Rururu Kondoh
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week!